Preliminary Inventory to the Robert R. Spitzer Papers, 1954-1994
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert R. Spitzer Papers,
1954-1994
85007
Spitzer, Robert R., 1922-
91 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 2 motion picture film reels (45 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, minutes, drafts of writings, printed matter, and audio-visual material, relating to Food for Peace, world food supply and agricultural production, and Wisconsin and United States politics, especially the 1968 and 1972 presidential campaigns of Richard M. Nixon.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; United States. Agency for International Development. Office of Food for Peace.; Agricultural assistance, American.; Food supply.; Food supply--Developing countries.; Presidents--United States--Election--1968.; Presidents--United States--Election--1972.; Agriculture.; Wisconsin--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; Moving-pictures.
Container List
- MAY DAY CELEBRATION, 1954
  Relates to a celebration organized by Robert Spitzer in Burlington, Wisconsin.
  - Correspondence (Box 1-8)
  - Newspaper issues
  - Organizational files
  - Photographs
  - Reports and transcripts. Relates to Congressional hearings on subversive activities
- H. C. SCHADEBERG CONGRESSIONAL CAMPAIGNS, 1960-1970
  Relates to Robert Spitzer's involvement in H. C. Schadeberg's campaigns for election to the House of Representatives from Wisconsin's First Congressional District.
  - Campaign materials (Box 9-18)
  - Correspondence
  - Minutes of meetings and conferences
  - Office files
  - Opinion polls
  - Press releases
  - Reports
  - Speech transcripts
- NIXON ELECTION AND ADMINISTRATION, 1967-1972
  - General (Box 19-32)
    - Clippings
    - Correspondence. Includes correspondence with Chuck Colson, Clifford Hardin, John Mitchell, Maurice Stans, and others, 1968-1972
    - Inaugural invitations, 1969
    - Minutes
    - Office files
    - Pamphlets
    - Subject files
  - Agricultural Advisory Committee. Primarily planning materials and printed and non-printed articles and reports, 1967-1968
  - Republican National Convention, 1968
- FOOD FOR PEACE, 1974-1979
  - General (Box 33-57)
    - Audio-visual materials
    - Correspondence
    - Memoranda
    - Minutes of meetings and seminars
    - Pamphlets
    - Reports
    - Serial issues
    - Subject files. Relates primarily to agriculture and food production
    - Trip materials. Extensive printed and non-printed materials, telegrams, questionnaires, grant proposals, notes, correspondence, clippings, tapes and transcripts of interviews
  - Agency for International Development. Press releases
  - United States Department of Agriculture. Notebook relating to specifications for food storage and transport
  - World Food Conference. Reports, 1974
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1968-1981
  - The American Challenge, 1980 (Box 58-64)
    - Correspondence. Includes important figures in the Nixon Administration
    - Drafts and manuscripts
    - Biographical sketches
    - Photographs
  - No Need for Hunger, 1981 (Box 65-90)
    - General
      - Clippings
      - Drafts
      - Graphs
      - Photographs
      - Reports
      - Source materials
      - Subject files
    - Agency for International Development. Relates to the possibility of Robert Spitzer's appointment as Coordinator of the agency, 1980-1981
    - World Food Program
  - The Family Organizer. Organizational notebook system developed by Robert Spitzer (Box 91)
  - Miscellaneous speeches and writings, 1989-
- MILWAUKEE SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING, 1981-
  - Newsletters, reports, pamphlets, and clippings, 1981- (Box 91)
- OVERSIZE FILE
  - Newspaper issues and materials primarily relating to the Nixon presidential campaign and administration; also includes materials relating to the Food for Peace program and the May Day celebration (Box 92-95)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE
  - "A World Hungry." An audio-visual package including filmstrips, printed material and a record (Box 96)
  - Two motion picture film reels (Film-shelf Film shelf)